Guide to the U.S. Wage Stabilization Board 1952 United Steelworkers of America Case 1947-1952
U.S. Wage Stabilization Board 1952 United Steelworkers of America Case
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
U.S. Wage Stabilization Board 1952 United Steelworkers of America Case, 1947- 1952
5069
United Steelworkers of America (USWA); U.S. Wage and Stabilization Board
4 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Transcripts and exhibits of a dispute between the American Smelting and Refining Co. and the United Steelworkers of America.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
A work stoppage in the steel industry was threatened for Dec. 31, 195l, since various companies engaged in ore mining and the production of basis steal had been unable to negotiate a new contract with the United Steel Workers of America to replace the one that expired on that date.
The union presented a list of 22 demands, relating to a general wage increase guaranteed annual wage, paid holidays, inequities, shift and geographical differentials, over time, improved vacation periods, and other economic and non economic demands.
The companies took the position that any increase in wages would not be in the best interest of the country since any increase in costs of producing steel would require an equivalent increase in steel prices.
The President referred the dispute to the Wage Stabilization Board, which in conjuation with the Office of Price Administration was endeavoring to develop an anti-inflation program during the period of the Korean War.
The Wage Stabilization Board appointed a special panel consisting of
Harry Shulman, Chairman
Ralph Seward
Admiral Earle W. Mills
John C. Bane, Jr.
Arnold Campo
Eli Oliver
at a procedural meeting on Jan. 7, 1952. On January 10, 1952 the Panel began hearings which continued until Feb. 16, 1952 The panel presented its report to the Executive Meeting of the Wage Stabilization Board on February 29, 1952 and the full Board discussed the recommendations of the panel until March 19, 1952. The final report of the Board was presented to the President on March 20, 1952.
SUBJECTS
Names:
United States Steel Corporation--Sources.; United States. Wage Stabilization Board; United Steelworkers of America--Sources.
Subjects:
Arbitration, Industrial--United States--Sources.; Iron and steel workers--Labor unions--Sources.
Form and Genre Terms:
Records (documents).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
RELATED MATERIALS
Related Collections:
5113: Ralph T. Seward Arbitration Transcripts and Exhibits
5328: Ralph T. Seward Papers
5700: Ralph T. Seward Additional Arbitration Files
CONTAINER LIST
- Steel Labor Case of 1952 - General (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Steel Labor Case of 1952 - General (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- USA Wage Stabilization Board: United Steelworkers of America v. Various Steel/Iron Ore Companies - Union Exhibits 8-10 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- United Steelworkers of America v. Various Steel and Iron Ore Companies - Union Exhibit 11 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- United Steelworkers of America v. Various Steel and Iron Ore Companies - Union Exhibits 15-21 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- United Steelworkers of America v. Various Steel and Iron Ore Companies - Union Exhibits 21A-25 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- United Steelworkers of America v. Various Steel and Iron Ore Companies - Union Exhibits 26A-26H (Box 1, Folder 7)
- United Steelworkers of America v. Various Steel and Iron Ore Companies - Union Exhibits 27-31 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Union Publicity (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Transcript of Proceedings: Executive Meeting of National Wage Stabilization Board (1 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Transcript of Proceedings: Executive Meeting of National Wage Stabilization Board (2 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Transcript of Proceedings: Executive Meeting of National Wage Stabilization Board (3 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Panel Report (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Report and Recommendations of the Wage Stabilization Board (Box 1, Folder 14)
- United Steelworkers of America (Case D-18-C) - Company Exhibits 1-5 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Steelworkers of America (Case D-18-C) - Company Exhibits 5A-8A (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Steelworkers of America (Case D-18-C) - Company Exhibits 9-13 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Steelworkers of America (Case D-18-C) - Company Exhibits 14-19 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Steelworkers of America (Case D-18-C) - Company Exhibits 19A-22 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Steelworkers of America (Case D-18-C) - Company Exhibits 23-29 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Case D-18-C: Atlanta Steel (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Case D-18-C: Allegheny Ludlum Steel (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Case D-18-C: US Steel (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Case D-18-C: Copperweld (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Case D-18-C: Follansbee (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Case D-18-C: Island Steel Company (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Case D-18-C: Jones and Laughlin Steel (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Case D-18-C: Youngstown (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Bethlehem Steel Company (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Case D-18-C: Republic Steel Corporation (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Case D-18-C: Iron Ore Companies Exhibits (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Iron Ore Panel Members Report (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Co-Publicity (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Case D-18-C: Mr. Stewart's File (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Union Exhibit 8 and Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Union Exhibit 9 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Union Exhibit 10 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Union Exhibit 11 and 15 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Union Exhibit 21 and 24 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Union Exhibits 25 and 26 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Company Exhibits and Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Union Exhibits 17A, 23, 26A, 26B (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Union Exhibits 26C, 26D, 26E, 26F, 27 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Union Exhibits 28, 29, 30, 30A (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Union Exhibit 2 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Union Exhibit 5 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Union Exhibit 6 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Union Exhibit 6 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Union Exhibit 6 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Union Exhibit 7 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Union Exhibit 7 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Union Exhibit 7 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Union Exhibit 17A (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Union Exhibit 22 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Union Exhibit 22 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Union Exhibit 23 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Union Exhibit 23 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Union Exhibit 26A (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Union Exhibit 26A (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Union Exhibit 26B (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Union Exhibit 26C (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Union Exhibit 26D (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Union Exhibit 26D (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Union Exhibit 26F (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Union Exhibit 28 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Union Exhibit 26E (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Union Exhibit 26F (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Union Exhibit 30 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Union Exhibit 30A (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Statement of Philip Murray (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Steelworker's Case for Wages, Pensions and Social Insurance (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Statement of Arthur Goldberg (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Union and Company Contract Proposals - US Steel Corporation (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Statement of Jules Backman (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Joh nH. Morse General Statement (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Productivity in the Steel Producing Divisions of United States Steel (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Statement of H.C. Stringfield (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Statement of R.C. Tyson (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Statement on Behalf of United States Steel Company Regarding Certain Miscellaneous Contract Demands (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Statement of Republic Steel Corporation (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Statement in Regard to the Demands of the Union on Jones and Laughlin Steel Corporation (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Statement of H. Tippit (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Statement of John W. Roberts (Box 3, Folder 49)
- 19551 Profit of Youngstown Sheet and Tube Company (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Statement of Jules Backman (Box 3, Folder 51)
- General Statement on Behalf of Inland Steel Company (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Statement of L.B. Hunter (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Statement of Hjalmar W. Johnson (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Bethlehem Exhibit 1-B (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Statement of Jules Backman (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Statement of Benjamin F. Fairless (Box 3, Folder 57)
- Statement of Thomas H. Sanders (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Statement for the Panel from Bethlehem Steel (Box 3, Folder 59)
- Companies Exhibit 18 (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Companies Exhibit 19 (Box 3, Folder 61)
- Companies Exhibit 12 (Box 3, Folder 62)
- Companies Exhibit 15A (Box 3, Folder 63)
- Statement of W.A. Paton (Box 3, Folder 64)
- Statement of Philip Murray (Box 3, Folder 65)
- Statement of Philip Murray (Box 3, Folder 66)
- Statement of Philip Murray (Box 3, Folder 67)
- Statement of Philip Murray (Box 3, Folder 68)
- (Box 3, Folder 69)
- Statement of Philip Murray (Box 3, Folder 69)
- Statement of Philip Murray (Box 3, Folder 70)
- Statement of Philip Murray (Box 3, Folder 71)
- Statement of Philip Murray (Box 3, Folder 72)
- The Steelworkers' Case for Wages, Pensions, and Social Insurance (Box 3, Folder 73)
- The Steelworkers' Case for Wages, Pensions, and Social Insurance (Box 3, Folder 74)
- Companies Exhibit No. 18 (Box 3, Folder 75)
- Companies Exhibit 19 (Box 3, Folder 76)
- Companies Exhibit 20 (Box 3, Folder 77)
- Companies Exhibit 17 (Box 3, Folder 78)
- Statement by Edward J. Hanley (Box 3, Folder 79)
- Youngstown Exhibit 4 (Box 3, Folder 80)
- Statement with Regard to the Unemployment Benefits Demand (Box 3, Folder 81)
- Statement of Jules Backman (Box 3, Folder 82)
- Statement of John C. Gail (Box 3, Folder 83)
- Statement of Jules Backman (Box 3, Folder 84)
- Statement of Jules Backman (Box 3, Folder 85)
- Companies Exhibit 20 (Box 3, Folder 86)
- Reply of the Steel Companies to the Union's Demand for Changes in the Seniority Provisions (Box 3, Folder 87)
- Statement of Joseph L. Block (Box 3, Folder 88)
- Statement of Thomas H. Sanders (Box 3, Folder 89)
- Statement of Frank Purnell (Box 3, Folder 90)
- Statement of C.M. White (Box 3, Folder 91)
- Memorandum of Argument on Behalf of Atlantic Steel Company (Atlanta, GA) (Box 3, Folder 92)
- Statement of L.B. Hunter (Box 3, Folder 93)
- Statements of D.K. McKamy and John V. Van Sickle (Box 3, Folder 94)
- Transcript of Proceedings: Wage Stabilization Board Steel Dispute (January 7, 1952) (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Transcript of Proceedings: Wage Stabilization Board Steel Dispute (January 10, 1952) (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Transcript of Proceedings: Wage Stabilization Board Steel Dispute (January 10, 1952 Part 2) (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Transcript of Proceedings: Wage Stabilization Board Steel Dispute (January 11, 1952) (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Transcript of Proceedings: Wage Stabilization Board Steel Dispute (January 11, 1952 Part 2) (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Transcript of Proceedings: Wage Stabilization Board Steel Dispute (January 12, 1952 Morning Session) (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Transcript of Proceedings: Wage Stabilization Board Steel Dispute (January 12, 1952 Afternoon Session) (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Official Report of Proceedings: Wage Stabilization Board Steel Industry Dispute (February 1, 1952) (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Official Report of Proceedings: Wage Stabilization Board Steel Industry Dispute (February 4, 1952) (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Official Report of Proceedings: Wage Stabilization Board Steel Industry Dispute (February 5, 1952) (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Official Report of Proceedings: Wage Stabilization Board Steel Industry Dispute (February 13, 1952 Part 1) (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Official Repot of Proceedings: Wage Stabilization Board Steel Industry Dispute (February 13, 1952 Part 2) (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Official Report of Proceedings: Wage Stabilization Board Steel Industry Dispute (February 6, 1952) (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Official Report of Proceedings: Wage Stabilization Board Steel Industry Dispute (February 7, 1952 Part 1) (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Official Report of Proceedings: Wage Stabilization Board Steel Industry Dispute (February 7, 1952 Part 2) (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Official Report of Proceedings: Wage Stabilization Board Steel Industry Dispute (February 8, 1952 Part 1) (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Official Report of Proceedings: Wage Stabilization Board Steel Industry Dispute (February 8, 1952 Part 2) (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Official Report of Proceedings: Wage Stabilization Board Steel Industry Dispute (February 9, 1952 Part 1) (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Official Report of Proceedings: Wage Stabilization Board Steel Industry Dispute (February 13, 1952) (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Official Repot of Proceedings: Wage Stabilization Board Steel Industry Dispute (February 14, 1952 Part 1) (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Official Report of Proceedings: Wage Stabilization Board Steel Industry Dispute (February 14, 1952 Part 2) (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Official Report of Proceedings: Wage Stabilization Board Steel Industry Dispute (February 15, 1952 Part 1) (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Official Transcript of Proceedings: Wage Stabilization Board Steel Industry Dispute (February 15, 1952 Part 2) (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Official Report of Proceedings: Wage Stabilization Board Steel Industry Dispute (February 16, 1952 Part 1) (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Transcript of Proceedings: Economic Stabilization Agency (February 29, 1952) (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Transcript of Proceedings: Economic Stabilization Agency (March 5, 1952) (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Transcript of Proceedings: Economic Stabilization Agency (March 6, 1952) (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Transcript of Proceedings: Economic Stabilization Agency (March 7, 1952) (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Transcript of Proceedings: Economic Stabilization Agency (March 19, 1952) (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Transcript of Proceedings: Economic Stabilization Agency (March 13, 1952) (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Transcript of Proceedings: Economic Stabilization Agency (March 15, 1952) (Box 4, Folder 31)